### **Epris Richardson**

### Software Engineer

Mooresville, NC 248-730-8645 eharrisburnett@gmail.com linkedin.com/in/eprishb https://www.eprisr.com

#### **PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY**

Experienced front-end engineer with more than 5 years in the industry. Successfully migrated an online application to React, reducing page load time by 7% in 3 months. Enhanced user experience, driving a 23% increase in conversion rates. Proficient in HTML, CSS, JavaScript, React, responsive design and API integration.

#### **WORK EXPERIENCE**

# Contract Software Engineer The Omega Agency LLC

Part-time - Feb 2024 - Present Raleigh, NC | Remote

### Marketing

- Engineered and maintained a social media app, elevating users 50% during an event, fostering connectivity for 100+ female entrepreneurs
- Developed a web-based calculator, resulting in a more efficient price estimation process.
- Developed a salable Angular and Typescript multi-color theme, improving the visual appeal and usability of an event reward platform.
- Collaborated with front-end and back-end developers to engineer an event reward mobile application.

# **Contract Graphic Designer** BHC ISS

Part-time - Oct 2023 - Present

Charlotte, NC | Remote

Fire & Life Safety Redistributor and Technician Training Center

- Maintained 8 company sites, optimizing for touch devices and SEO, resulting in a 12% increase in organic traffic and user satisfaction.
- Enhanced UI/UX and accessibility for 8 web applications, resulting in an increase in user engagement and improved SEO performance.
- Mentor designers on basic HTML & CSS markup for product pages, email templates, and marketing materials.

## Software Engineer WECO Hospitality

Full-time - Jul 2022 - Aug 2023

Acton, MA | Remote

#### Hospitality

- Collaborated to migrate an online application from WordPress to React in 3 months, improving security and scalability, and decreasing page load time by 7%.
- Implemented efficient backed API data handling processes for ordering using Axios, leading to a 15% reduction in data transfer errors and a better overall user-experience.
- Integrated Google Analytics to gain valuable insights into user behavior, product performance, and application usage, leading to data-driven decisions for continuous improvement.

## Web Developer & Graphic Designer

Brooks Equipment / BHC ISS

Full-time - Feb 2019 - Jul 2022 Charlotte, NC | Hybrid

Fire & Life Safety Redistributor and Technician Training Center

**Graphic Designer** 

Bradley Co.

Full-time - May 2017 - May 2018

Southfield, MI

**Promotional Merchandising Agency** 

**Project Manager** 

Part-time - Sep 2014 - May 2018

Applet Social (Formerly I Am Creative LLC)

Detroit, MI

No-Code App Development Startup

**EDUCATION** 

**Bachelors of Fine Arts in Visual Communication** 

The Art Institute of Michigan

Farmington Hills, MI - Jul 2010 - Jun 2013

**CERTIFICATIONS** 

**Front-End Web Development** 

Nov 2018 - Present

Udacity - Grow with Google

**SKILLS** 

Soft Skills: Collaborative, Communication, Problem-Solving, Self-Starter

Programming Languages: JavaScript, Typescript

Web: Accessibility (A11y), Search Engine Optimization Strategy

Version Control: AWS, Git, GitHub

Frameworks / Libraries: Angular, ExpressJS, Next.js, Node.JS, React

Database: Firebase, MongoDB, PostgreSQL

Testing: Jest, Mock Service Worker (MSW), React Testing Library

Other: Heroku, Sentry, Vercel